<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://thedigitalstockade.github.io/">
    <title>The Digital Stockade</title>
    <link href="https://thedigitalstockade.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" >
    <link href="https://thedigitalstockade.github.io/" >
    <updated>2025-10-24T01:10:45Z</updated>
    <id>https://thedigitalstockade.github.io/</id>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Welcome
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-10-24T01:10:30Z</updated>
            <id>https://thedigitalstockade.github.io//</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;h1 id=&quot;a-href-https-thedigitalstockade-github-io-about-target-blank-class-external-link-about-a&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thedigitalstockade.github.io/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a researcher who uses digital techniques to explore early Australian Colonial convict history. I also have a special interest in early industrial systems and processes. This site however is less about my research (although you may get snippets from time to time) and more about the digital tools and techniques that I use (or bump into) that may also assist you in your own Archaeological, Digital Humanities or History research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not intend to write in depth tutorials on programming languages or methods (There are much better tutors on the web for advanced programming methods than me), but rather to produce a grab-bag of practical examples to ‘lower the barrier of entry’ to digital techniques for new and existing researchers so that you may add them to your repertoire and start exploring the past in new ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of this site as an open-access version of my own digital notebook. Much of what I post here is captured directly from my personal Obsidian notes. It’s not a formal academic publication, but a place for me to share my thoughts and working code as I develop it, including my experiments with AI for historical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-you-ll-find-inside&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;What You&#39;ll Find Inside&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things easy to find, I’ve broken the posts into a few categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Function in 5:&lt;/strong&gt; These are the shortest posts. They&#39;re quick, copy-and-paste code snippets designed to solve one small problem, fast. No background, just the function, what it needs, and an example of it in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Digital Toolkit:&lt;/strong&gt; These are more practical, step-by-step guides for a specific tool or method I&#39;ve found useful, like a short tutorial for solving a common research problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detailed Discussions:&lt;/strong&gt; From time to time, I&#39;ll post longer, almost-scientific discussions. These are my musings on broader digital history topics, ethical questions, or the theories behind the digital techniques we use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have genuine questions please feel free to reach out via the form on the contact page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://thedigitalstockade.github.io//" >
        </entry>
</feed>
